[Music] typescript validate your javascript
[音乐]typescript 通过静态类型检查提前验证您的 javascript
ahead of time with static type checking javascript is a dynamic language where
javascript 是一种动态语言，
we can do all kinds of crazy things like reference variables that don't
我们可以在其中做各种疯狂的事情，例如不
exist or work with objects of an unknown shape the code is interpreted by a
存在的引用变量或使用未知形状的对象代码由 a 解释
browser but if your code is broken you won't
浏览器，但如果你的代码被破坏了，你
catch it until runtime when the browser rows an error
直到运行时才会捕捉到它，当浏览器行错误
typescript prevents errors like this from ever happening by extending
打字稿通过扩展带有类型的 javascript 来防止这样的错误发生时，
javascript with types the language is a strict superset of
该语言是 javascript 的严格超集，
javascript which means when you open up a ts file you can write plain javascript
这意味着当你打开一个 ts 文件，您可以编写普通的 javascript
with all of its extra features being completely optional but notice in
，其所有额外功能都是完全可选的，但请注意
the code here how the ide is providing feedback about using a
此处的代码中 ide如何提供有关使用
variable that doesn't exist instead of fixing this issue weeks later
不存在的变量的反馈，而不是几周
in a stack trace after the company has lost millions of dollars we can fix it
后在公司之后的堆栈跟踪中修复此问题 已经损失了数百万美元我们现在可以在这里修复它
right here right now the reason we get this instant feedback
我们得到这个即时反馈的原因
is because typescript behaves like a compiled language
是因为 typescript 的行为就像一个编译的 lang  uage
where javascript is the compilation target you can run the typescript
，其中 javascript 是编译目标，您可以使用 tsc 命令运行 typescript
compiler using the tsc command it will take the
编译器，它将获取
ts file and transpile it into vanilla javascript
ts 文件并将其转换为 vanillajavascript
and you can choose any flavor of javascript you want if you need to
，如果您需要
target ancient browsers and that means you can use the latest
针对古代浏览器，您可以选择任何您想要的 javascript 风格，这意味着您 可以使用 javascript 的最新
and greatest syntax features of javascript without having to worry if
和最好的语法特性，而不必担心
they'll be supported in an older environment your typescript project will
它们是否会在旧环境中得到支持，你的 typescript 项目
likely have a ts config file which provides an infinite number of
可能会有一个 ts 配置文件，它提供了无数种
ways to customize the behavior of the compiler
方法来自定义编译器的行为，
but the primary goal of typescript is to enable static typing
但是 typescript 的主要目标是启用静态类型，
one way it achieves that is by allowing you to annotate your code with types
它实现的一种方式是允许您使用类型注释代码
we can strongly type a variable using a colon followed by its type like a string
boolean or number that's known as an explicit type if we
then try to assign its value as the wrong type we get an error
然后我们尝试将它的值分配为错误的类型，
alternatively if we set an initial value it will implicitly infer the type
如果我们设置一个初始值，则会得到一个错误，它会隐式推断 t 是的，
however there may be cases where you want to opt out of this behavior
但是在某些情况下，您可能希望选择退出此行为，
in which case you can annotate with the any type that allows you to loosely type
在这种情况下，您可以使用任何类型进行注释，以允许您在使用数组时轻松键入
or opt out of type checking when working with an array
或选择退出类型检查
use brackets to strongly type a list in addition you can define your own custom
此外，您可以定义自己的自定义
types and interfaces which is especially powerful when
类型和接口，这在处理对象时特别强大，
working with objects the car interface here defines various types
这里的汽车接口定义
of the properties on an object we can then apply the interface to a plain
了对象上的各种类型的属性，然后我们可以将该接口应用于普通的
javascript object the beauty of having strongly typed code
javascript 对象。强类型代码的美妙之处
is that we get autocomplete everywhere in our ide
在于 我们在我们的 ide 中到处都可以自动完成
we don't have to jump back and forth to documentation or dig through stack
我们不必来回跳转到文档或挖掘堆栈
traces to figure out why our code's not working
跟踪来找出为什么我们的代码不起作用
if you like typescript as much as i do consider becoming a pro member at
如果你喜欢 typescript 就像我考虑成为 fireship io 的专业会员一样
fireship io for the next few days everything will be 40 off including
在接下来的几天里，包括终身会员在内的所有商品都将享受 40 折优惠，
lifetime memberships thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
感谢您的收看，我们下期再见